hi I'm Greg and chairs and I just got an
article published on strength coach calm
yesterday and it's lighted some
questions about how to do some of these
exercises so I thought I film a short
video actually it's going to be a
three-part series this is part 1 in this
video I'm going to go through the supine
or the bridging progressions that I used
and I've been doing these for a couple
years with my client to my athletes so
I've developed a pretty good system I
don't just start people out by saying
okay
you look strong I'm going to throw 315
pounds in your lab and do some improv
I started off slowly and make sure they
master the basics before progressing on
a more advanced variation so a lot of
people will mistakenly think that squads
Dedalus lung is the best glute exercise
and these people haven't measured the
glute activity like I have I spent you
know a couple months performing every
single workout I did with wires and
electro hooked to my glutes and then I
performed special experiments and then I
also tested four different other four
different people including myself and
the squatting and dead lifting and
lunging movements can get you up to you
know usually between thirty and fifty
five percent of MBC the exercises some
of them though I'm going to show you
today can get you up to 120 percent so
you know they can triple or quadruple
their glute activity that you can get
there lifting weights up or lifting
weights upwards the glutes don't have to
maximally contract when you move weight
forward with bent legs like you'll see
today that's the way to get maximum
glute activation so anyway I'm going to
take you through a series of
the first and most important blue
exercise is always the hip flexor
stretch so you have to get people to be
able to open up their hips flexible hip
flexes lets you hyper extend the hips
which which is the maximal contractions
are in for the glute so you have to be
able to do that to tell your flexors
prevent the gluts from contracture so
that's the first glute exercise of the
hip flexor stretch and the most
important if your if your hip flexors
are tight second is just the glute
bridge okay
that's nothing then a single leg glute
bridge then we increase the range of
motion we can do this a couple different
ways so one of the ways and this is the
hanging method okay
and then a single egg
yeah you can increase resistance if we
want no an alternative that means
nothing just these two pictures so here
I can do there or there so some of them
were a little practical if you're a
strength coach training a lot of
athletes at once but I owned a private
gym in Scottsdale and I have a luxury of
being able to be very creative and take
time because I wasn't training you know
30 people at once though
now we get into the really difficult
exercises where you can really load up
the glutes and some people think well
that looks dangerous and I tell them
we're talking about the glutes the most
powerful muscle these were meant these
are you know workhorse of the human body
so you don't just start off with this
but you work up to it so this is 315
pounds this is actually very light for
me I can use 400 bucks on for 10 reps no
problem and I just use a Hampton thick
bobcat roll it over me
so what
once again dividual gets good adapt
nettle elevate them we can do the hip
thrust variation so and now the last and
most advanced method is to combine
barbells the bottle with band so I was
already done
so this method here is the most advanced
variation and this is the one that will
get good activity up to 120% so for this
one we just get it the position that's
tough so that's the bridging supine
progression the next three series I'll
go over the quadruple and prone
progression in any objection
external rotation progression thanks a
lot